Guide to the Tom Triman Films, 1970s-2000s RL.10062
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Tom Triman films
circa 1970-2010
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Triman, Tom
RL.10062
2.5 Linear Feet
The Tom Triman Films are comprised of 132 super 8mm reels and one VHS videocassette, containing the productions of horror movie fan/historian/critic Tom Triman (1952-2010).
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials may require production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact Research Services before coming to use this collection.
The collection may contain materials to which the Acknowledgment of Legal Responsibilities and Privacy Rights form applies. Patrons must sign this form before using the collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Collection Overview
The Tom Triman Films are comprised of 132 super 8mm reels and one VHS videocassette, containing the productions of horror movie fan/animator/writer Tom Triman (1952-2010). The bulk of the reels are elements for larger works, which here include Butterfly Man, Gunfire and Holy Water, and Pentagram. The collection also contains several commercial films released on super 8mm film, including 2001 A Space Odyssey, Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde, and Frankenstein.
Arrangement
The reels are undated and arranged generally by function. Series 1 contains the bulk of the reels and are largely untitled elements. Series 2 contains what appear to be finished works, as well as commercially released studio films purchased by Triman. Series 3 contains one VHS videocassette, a computer animation demo tape by Triman. Series four contains a set of three Scary Monsters Magazine Sam Scare cards.
Provenance
The Tom Triman Films were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2011.
Biographical note
Tom Triman (1952-2010) was an afficianado of horror films, a contributor to Scary Monsters Magazine, and an animator and filmmaker who often worked in super 8mm film. His published film work includes A Spark of Being (1986, 6 min) and You Dirty Rat (1982, 52 min).
Super 8; Audiovisual materials; Home movies; Triman, Tom
- Element reels, 1970s-2000s; 1
  - Super 8mm reel, Beth (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0083)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 34; Someday Soon I'll... (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0032)
  - Super 8mm reel, "Someday Soon" visual (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0081)
  - Super 8mm reel, YDR (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0075)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 4 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0001)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 6 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0002)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 7 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0003)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 8 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0004)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 9 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0005)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 10 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0006)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 11 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0007)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 12 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0008)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 13 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0009)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 14 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0010)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 15 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0011)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 16 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0012)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 16 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0013)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 17 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0014)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 18 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0015)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 19 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0016)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 20 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0017)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 21 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0018)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 21 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0019)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 22 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0020)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 23 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0021)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 24 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0022)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 25 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0023)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 26 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0024)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 27 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0025)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 28 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0026)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 29 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0027)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 30 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0028)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 31 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0029)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 32 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0030)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 33 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0031)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 36 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0033)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 37 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0034)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 38 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0035)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 39 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0036)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 40 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0037)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 42 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0038)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 43 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0039)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 45 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0040)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 47 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0041)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 48 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0042)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 49 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0043)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 50 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0044)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 51 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0045)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 53 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0046)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 55 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0047)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 56 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0048)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 57 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0049)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 58 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0050)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 58 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0051)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 59 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0052)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 61 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0053)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 62 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0054)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 63 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0055)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 64 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0056)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 65 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0057)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 66 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0058)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 68 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0059)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 69 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0060)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 70 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0061)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 71 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0062)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 72 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0063)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 73 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0064)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 74 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0065)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 75 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0066)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 76 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0067)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 77 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0068)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 78 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0069)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 79 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0070)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 80 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0071)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 82 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0072)
  - Super 8mm reel, Reel 83 (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0073)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0074)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0076)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0077)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0078)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0079)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0080)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0082)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0084)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 1, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0085)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0086)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0087)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0088)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0089)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0090)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0091)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0092)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0093)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0094)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0095)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0096)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0097)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0098)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0099)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0100)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0101)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0102)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0103)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0104)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0105)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0106)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0107)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0108)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0109)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0110)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0111)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0112)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0113)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0114)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0115)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0116)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0117)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0118)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0119)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 2, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0120)
  - Super 8mm reel, untitled (Box 3, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0121)
- Finished films and commercial reels, 1970s-2000s; 2
  - Butterfly Man first part, undated; 5
    - Super 8mm reel (Box 3, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0127)
  - Butterfly Man, undated; 4
    - Super 8mm reel (Box 3, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0126)
  - Gunfire and Holy Water, undated; 8
    - Super 8mm reel (Box 3, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0128)
  - Pentagram, undated
    - Super 8mm reel (Box 3, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0124)
      Preservation
      Sent to AV Geeks for transfer digitization on May 22, 2014.
  - 2001 A Space Odyssey, 1968; 2
    - Super 8mm reel (Box 3, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0122)
  - 2001 A Space Odyssey, 3
    - Super 8mm reel (Box 3, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0125)
  - Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde, 1941; 6
    - Super 8mm reel (Box 3, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0131)
  - Frankenstein, 1931; 7
    - Super 8mm reel (Box 3, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0132)
  - Hamlet on TV, undated; 9
    - Super 8mm reel (Box 3, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0129)
  - untitled, 1970s-2000s; 10
    - Super 8mm reel (Box 3, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0123)
    - Super 8mm reel (Box 3, Film-reel RL10062-FS8-0130)
- Video, circa 1990s; 3
  - Tom Triman, Computer Animation Demo Reel, 1970s-2000s; 11
    - VHS video (Box 3, Video-cassette RL10062-VHS-0001)
- Other materials
  - Scary Monsters Magazine Sam Scare Scare-Cards, circa 2006; 3 items (Box 3)